# **Eric Um**

Katy, TX | LinkedIn | Website | Github | 615-580-9641 | eric@umericdev.com

#### **PROFILE**

Application Analyst primarily using Salesforce to provide data analysis support, end-to-end testing, and configuration with personal experience in various Azure resources, relational databases, and ETL pipelines. I would love to join a team to grow with and apply my skills to make an impact as I continue my personal studies towards development.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS & PLATFORMS**

Data Engineering | ETL/ELT, Data Integration, Data Processing, Dataloader
Programming | Python, SQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS
Database | PostgreSQL, Azure SQL Database, Azure Blob Storage, Data Warehouse
Cloud Platforms | Salesforce, Microsoft Azure, Azure Synapse, Azure Data Factory (ADF)

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Acadia Healthcare

## **Salesforce Application Analyst**

May 2021 - Present

- Built Salesforce flows to streamline user provisioning processes, reducing administrative workload by 20%.
- Led user automation project with DevOps and Development teams, providing field mapping direction and implementing logic for enhanced data accuracy, duplicate prevention, and system efficiency.
- Devised Excel-based system for precise onboarding of intake and business users, ensuring accurate access granting.
- Initiated the creation and execution of test scripts using Azure DevOps to thoroughly test new features, ensuring the absence of bugs and contributing to meeting sprint deadlines for the application's success.

## **Service Desk Analyst**

September 2020 – May 2021

- Created an accelerated 17-page training guide with a comprehensive table of contents for new hires, enabling efficient onboarding and rapid familiarity with key technologies and challenges.
- Resolved 1000+ tickets, promptly diagnosing and solving hardware and software issues, ensuring efficient solutions and strong customer service.

## **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS**

Associate of Information Technology Major Cyber Security

August 2018 – December 2020

Motlow Community College

**DP 900 - Azure Data Fundamentals** 

DP 203 - Azure Data Engineer Associate

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Consistently achieved top ratings and most reviews in customer service desk evaluations.
- Reached the semifinals for code launch in Houston startups for a mock-up idea of ai app to estimate task time
- Contributed 40.14% of task completed of team of 6 and consistently resolved an average of 64 support tickets weekly, demonstrating operational leadership impact on Salesforce support.

#### PERSONAL PROJECTS

# Extract, Transform, Load Anxiety & Depression Symptoms Data [View Github]

**Description:** Employed ETL processes to analyze depression data, exploring race-related differences in anxiety and depression symptoms to identify trends.

Tools Used: CDC API, Visual Studio with Python, PostgreSQL, pgAdmin4, Flourish

## **Project Highlights:**

- Gathered authoritative data on anxiety and depression symptoms through CDC API.
- Leveraged Visual Studio with Python for efficient data extraction, transformation, and loading.
- Implemented PostgreSQL as a reliable data storage solution.
- Utilized pgAdmin4 for seamless data querying and management.
- Created engaging visual graphs for data representation using Flourish.

## Google API Integration for Houston Restaurants [View Github]

**Description:** Integrated Google API to retrieve data on Houston restaurants, utilizing Azure data tools to process and analyze API data.

**Tools Used:** Google Places API, Visual Studio, Azure Pipelines, Azure Synapse Studio, Flourish

# **Project Highlights:**

- Obtained comprehensive data on Houston restaurants through Google Places API.
- Applied Visual Studio for effective data extraction and preparation for database storage.
- Facilitated data transformation and loading into the data lake with Azure Pipelines.
- Utilized Azure Synapse Studio for creating SQL scripts to refine and analyze data.
- Created a visual chart for clear data representation using Flourish.

## Web Portfolio with Data Engineering Projects [View Github]

**Description:** Developed a web portfolio showcasing various data engineering projects, emphasizing front-end skills and data-driven solutions.

**Tools Used:** Visual Studio, Azure Storage Account, Azure Static Website

#### **Project Highlights:**

- Created a front-end website using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript using Visual Studio.
- Utilized Azure Storage Account for data management and hosting of the static website.
- Deployed and served static web content using Azure Static Website.